

# Salvador Olvera Nava

Full Stack Developer

Ruby on Rails / React - Redux

@ salvador.olvera@outlook.com



Salvador-ON



#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Full-Stack Remote Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating web applications with intuitive UX, UI effects, and responsive design. I have been extensively involved in developing web applications such as Front-end user interface, and Backend database management. I have experience working with remote teams, and advanced proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rail, and React/Redux. With 5 years of experience in the tech field as a Mechatronic Engineer.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Jr Full-Stack Developer.**

Microverse Web Development Program - Remote.

2020

Worked remotely doing pair programming with colleagues from other parts of the world, increasing the code quality of the developed projects.

Built over 30 Front-end and Back-end projects during the program. Using different technologies.

Made unit and integration tests on projects, to keep bugs out of production, helping to improve the quality of the projects.

Mentored new developers, helping and guiding them in the coding development. Reviewed and tested their codes and giving feedback to improve it, and helping them to understand some concepts.

**Technologies used:** 

(Ruby on Rails)

React/Redux

[ JavaScript ]

Webpack

HTML5/CSS3/SASS





Tridi Mx.

## **Chief Operating Officer.**

2016 - 2019

Supervised and lead the daily operations of the company including manufacturing operations, engineering, purchase, human resources, and administration.

Developed the annual strategic plan to improve the key performance indicators, improving production efficiency by 15%.

Managed the logistics entry of the company to the Stratasys Global Manufacturing Network. From the development of the start plan of the new production lines to the startup, and lead the daily manufacturing operations.

Ensured proper management of resources, distribution of goods and services to customers, and supply chain.

**Technologies used:** 

Ganttic )

( Python )

Google Spreadsheets









## **Adittive Manufacture Chief Officer.**

2015 - 2016

Developed and implemented a quality validation system for the manufactured items, helping to avoid sending defective items.

Developed and implemented a Manufacturing Execution System, helping the company to track and capture data, of the processes and outcomes of the manufacturing process.

Planned and executed daily production schedules, supervised, coordinated, and evaluated Human Resources to ensure daily production.

Standardized the manufacturing operations processes including CAD file preparations, manufacturing, post-treatments, maintenance, and shipments.

**Technologies used:** 

Embedded Systems

Solidworks / Inventor

Google Spreadsheets

# Jr Engineer.

2014 - 2015

Researched and developed the post-treatments. Helping to improve the quality of the pieces.

Developed and implemented tools and jigs, with the aim of reducing scrap and ensuring product quality and increasing the safety of the processes.

Researched and developed the improvement of the software parameters and hardware on the additive manufacturing equipment. Improving the visual quality of the pieces, reducing scrap by 10%, and post-treatment times by 15%.

**Technologies used:** 

Arduino Raspberry Pi

Python

**Google Spreadsheets** 

Solidworks / Inventor

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### Front-end

☐ HTML/CSS/SASS

Bootstrap

React/Redux JavaScript

Adobe CS (Ai, Ps, Pr)

### Back-end

Ruby/Rails

**SQL** 

Skills

**Project Management** 

Lean Manufacturing

**Continual Improvement Process Problem Solving** Code Review

Linux Netlify Git Heroku

**Unit Testing** Wireframing Mockups Teamwork

Creativity **Proactivity Pair Programming** 

## **EDUCATION**

## **Full-Stack Developer.**

Microverse Web Development Program.

During this program, I improved my development skills using: HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL JavaScript, React, and Redux.

I was selected to be a Student Mentor: Helping the new students through the program.

2020

Tridi Mx.

Tridi Mx.

### Mechatronic Engineering. Universidad del Valle de México.

2011 - 2015 Manager Mentor.

## Harvard Business School.

2012

**Continuous Process** Automatization. Festo.

2012

Solidworks CSWA.

Solidworks. 2012

## **AWARDS**

#### Laureate Award for **Excellence in Robotic Engineering**

Team leader of Mexico team and finalist at the Laureate Award for Excellence in Robotics Engineering, Second edition, 2015.

## **LANGUAGE**

Spanish (Native)

**English** (Professional)